<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: utilities | Yet Another Android Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/blog/categories/utilities/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-10-08T19:46:25+03:00</updated>
  <id>http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Oleksandr Yefremov]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Throttling bandwidth for Android app on physical device (not only http).]]></title>
    <link href="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/blog/2014/10/08/Throttling-bandwidth-on-Android-device/"/>
    <updated>2014-10-08T14:41:15+03:00</updated>
    <id>http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/blog/2014/10/08/Throttling-bandwidth-on-Android-device</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The other day I needed to throttle (limit bandwidth) of video streaming application on Android for testing purposes. iPhone has this feature built in since iOS6.</p>

<!-- more -->

<p>As I use Mac OS, I will list instructions for it. Options that I considered:</p>

<p><strong>1. Use <code>emulator -netspeed gsm</code></strong><br>
    I need to be able to do the same thing on real device as well, so strike off.</p>

<p><strong>2. Root phone, install or hack your own <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.oxplot.bradybound&amp;hl=en">application</a> which will limit bandwidth (or play with <a href="http://stackoverflow.com/questions/4658619/how-to-use-iptables-in-an-android-application">iptables</a>)</strong><br>
    Not an option, cause I need clean stock firmware on device</p>

<p><strong>3. Throttle bandwidth on WiFi router, if it supports such a feature.</strong><br>
    And everybody connected to the same router will suffer. Besides, with some models you&#39;d need to restart router every time you want to turn on/off throttling.</p>

<p><strong>3. If you have laptop (or PC with WiFi interface), connect to network via Ethernet, setup Internet Sharing from Ethernet to WiFi, connect device to laptop and use <a href="http://nshipster.com/network-link-conditioner/">Network Link Conditioner</a> on Mac or similar software which is easy and straightforward but can only limit all connections together.</strong><br>
    This is the easiest way, if you don&#39;t mind all your connections on both laptop and smartphone slowed down. NLC also able to simulate packet drops and latency.</p>

<p><strong>4. Charles proxy</strong><br>
Lets you throttle specific host accessed with HTTP(S). You can also set breakpoints on everything.
Keep in mind that free version shows &quot;waiting popups&quot; occasionally and restarts every 30 minutes.</p>

<p><a href="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/images/throttling/Charles proxy throttling.png"><img class="caption" style="background-color:white;" src="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/images/throttling/Charles proxy throttling.png" width="267" height="250 " /></a></p>

<p>Since I might need to use RTP (or smth not HTTP) in future, let&#39;s take one more step.</p>

<p><strong>5. IceFloor or managing system firewall</strong><br>
&quot;<a href="http://www.hanynet.com/icefloor/">IceFloor</a> is a graphic frontend for <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/PF_%28firewall%29">PF</a>&quot;.</p>

<p>First we go through step 3 above: connect Ethernet, turn on Internet Sharing, connect our device to laptop. Make sure it works, browse some page or stream video from your app. 
In IceFloor navigate to <strong>Interfaces</strong> tab, click <code>Update</code> button and locate Ethernet and bridge interfaces. In my case it was <code>en0</code>, <code>bridge100</code>.</p>

<p><a href="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/images/throttling/IceFloor Interfaces.png"><img class="caption" style="background-color:white;" src="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/images/throttling/IceFloor Interfaces.png" width="374" height="214 " /></a></p>

<p>Now to <strong>NAT</strong> tab, check &quot;Share internet connection&quot; and select interfaces that you located on previous screen.</p>

<p><a href="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/images/throttling/IceFloor NAT.png"><img class="caption" style="background-color:white;" src="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/images/throttling/IceFloor NAT.png" width="374" height="214 " /></a></p>

<p>Last step, <strong>Firewall</strong> tab, select &quot;Outbound (NAT clients)&quot; list, add required protocols to &quot;Services in selected Address Group&quot; (I just added &quot;All services&quot;). And here is the thing we&#39;ve been chasing - Max. Bandwidth. Note, that we can&#39;t specify packet drop rate or latency here. If you need those as well as bandwidth control, NLC in step 3 is what I would use (or if you use HTTP as a protocol, Charles also can do this).</p>

<p><a href="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/images/throttling/IceFloor Firewall.png"><img class="caption" style="background-color:white;" src="http://oleksandr-yefremov.github.io/images/throttling/IceFloor Firewall.png" width="374" height="214 " /></a></p>

<p>Click &quot;Start PF&quot; and you are good to go. Hit &quot;Apply&quot; every time you change any setting. To see if limit works for me, I usually go to <a href="http://speedtest.net">http://speedtest.net</a>.</p>

<p>We can continue using Charles for debugging</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
